Inventory of the Grigore Constantinescu papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Grigore Constantinescu papers
1931-1980
81087
Hoover Institution Archives
6 manuscript boxes (2.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, diaries, minutes, radio broadcast transcripts, memoranda, and phonotapes, relating to communism in Romania, Romanian émigré politics, the Assembly of Captive European Nations, and Radio Free Europe.
Constantinescu, Grigore, 1896-1980.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of all sound recordings in the collection are available. To view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection(s)
Biographical/Historical Note
A Romanian diplomat, Constantinescu served as the minister-counsellor to Great Britain, from 1946 to 1947, and served within the Comitetul National Roman (Romanian National Committee), the post-World War II Romanian democratic government-in-exile.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, diaries, minutes, radio broadcast transcripts, memoranda, and phonotapes, relating to communism in Romania, Romanian émigré politics, the Assembly of Captive European Nations, and Radio Free Europe.
ACEN (Organization); Radio Free Europe.; Anti-communist movements.; Diplomats--Romania.; Romania--Emigration and immigration.; Romania--Politics and government--1944-1989.
- Personal papers, 1956-1980 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with the Romanian National Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with the Romanian National Committee, 1956-1963 (Box 1)
- Diaries, 1950-1951, 1953-1954, 1969 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes personal, diplomatic, and political information, relating to exiles, contacts in the Foreign Office, and information used for radio broadcasts.
- Sound recording of various speakers performing the first lines of the "To Be or Not to Be" soliloquy from Hamlet, 2 open reel tapes Physical tapes are labelled 012081 and 012178 respectively. (Box 2)
  Access
  Use copy number: 81087_a_0009111
  Content note
  The clips sound like they are culled from commercial disc sources.
- Tracing the Hound of the Baskervilles, 1 sound tape reel (Box 2)
  Use copy reference number: 81087_a_0009946
  Tracing the Hound of the Baskervilles Sherlock Holmes Society of London Wednesday, October 6th, 1965, 7:30 evening
- Correspondence with the Romanian National Committee, 1964 (Box 2)
- Correspondence with the Romanian National Committee, 1965 (Box 2)
- Correspondence with the Romanian National Committee, 1970 (Box 2)
- Personal Correspondence, 1946-1979 (Box 3)
- (Box 3)
- Memorandum on the Treatment of Political Prisoners in Romania, 1959 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1950-1972 (Box 3)
- Correspondence (Box 3)
- Correspondence from and concerning Mrs. Titulescu regarding her role during World War II (Box 3)
- Broadcasts to Romania for Radio Free Europe through the BBC in London, 1957-1966 (Box 4)
- Broadcasts to Romania for Radio Free Europe through the BBC in London files, 1967-1973 (Box 5)
- Photograph and newspaper clippings (Box 5)
- Correspondence, mementos, diary, radio broadcast transcripts, travel documents, memorabilia, photographs and other materials, 1946-1950 (Box 6)